PERSONAL PROFILE

I'm a senior software developer with more than 10 years of experience. I have worked at both small startups and large organizations. While I'm a proficient full-stack developer, my expertise is in building scalable backend services (API services).

CONTACT ME AT

jags84@gmail.com

jags84.dev

+34 622 410 305

https://github.com/jags84

SKILLS SUMMARY

- Ruby on Rails
- API's
- JSON:API
- JavaScript
- Git
- CI/CD
- Google Cloud
- Ubuntu Server
- PostgreSQL
- CoffeeScript
- Handlebars
- jQuery
- Ethereum Apps
- Web3 JS
- Cake PHP
- ElasticSearch
- MarionetteJS

JUAN GONZALEZ SANTANA

SENIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Backend Developer

Selectra | Madrid | https://selectra.es | Jan 2018 - present

- Develop several applications and APIs using Ruby on Rails, Go and Nodeis
- Implement CI/CD for the applications using CloudBuild from Google
- Manage Google Cloud infrastructure

Lead Backend Developer

DADA | Remote - NYC | https://dada.nyc | Feb 2015 - present

- Develop DADA's application using Ruby and Rails as backend and Marionette.js for the frontend
- Develop DADA notification system using Node.js and Socket.io
- Develop Dada Marketplace app on Ethereum Blockchain using solidity and web3js
- Maintenance and configuration of servers (Ubuntu)
- Implement CI/CD for the applications

Freelance Backend Developer

Picketfencer | Remote - NJ | Jul 2017 - Jul 2020

 Develop new functionalities for Picketfencer application using Ruby on Rails

Web Application Developer

Ries, Inc | Caracas | Jul 2012 - Feb 2014

- Develop and improve AlliHay application using Ruby on Rails
- Develop Celuseguros application using Cake PHP

IT Analyst

Natural Harvest Resource | Caracas | Jun 2011 - Jan 2014

- IT Support
- Manage server and network

Internships

Funvisis | Caracas | Aug 2011 - Oct 2011

• Develop application to handle communications inside the organization using Ruby on Rails

Computer Consultant

Casa Arturo Uslar Pietri Foundation | Caracas | Jul 2007 - Jul 2010

- Develop a website for the Arturo Uslar Foundation
- Develop an application to manage the Foundation database using PHP
- IT Support

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

Bachelor of Computer Science

Central University of Venezuela | Dec 2016

Science High School Diploma

Emil Friedman School | Jul 2003

ACCELERATOR

Matter 7 Accelerator

Matter Accelerator | New York City | Jun 2017 - Oct 2017

COURSES / CERTIFICATIONS

Liderazgo en Tecnologia

Udemy | Online | Sep 2020

Scrum Master + Liderar Equipos Scrum y Ágil

Udemy | Online | Sep 2020

Ruby on Rails Specialization

Coursera | Online | May 2017

Development of Mobile Solutions: Android

Diplomadosonline endorsed by the Central University of Venezuela | January 2017 - May 2017

Angular 2 + Rails 5 Bootcamp

Udemy | Online | April 2017